{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nassau","incorrectAnswers":["Castries","Banjul","Podgorica"],"question":"What is the capital city of Bahamas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","The Middle East","Central Asia"],"question":"From which part of the world do peaches originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shaking My Head","incorrectAnswers":["Sometimes Men Hate","Special Man, Him","Soothe Me Honey"],"question":"What do people mean when type the letters 'SMH' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mickey Rooney","incorrectAnswers":["Mick Jagger","Mickey Rourke","Micky Cohen"],"question":"After who was Mickey Mouse named?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Qatar","Lebanon","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"In which country is the city of Alexandria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Peter Rabbit","incorrectAnswers":["Watership Down","Winny The Pooh","Black Beauty"],"question":"What story features flopsy, mopsy and cottontail?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tobey Maguire","incorrectAnswers":["Warwick Davis","Timothy Spall","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in both Spider-Man and Roseanne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Amok Trey","incorrectAnswers":["Shawarma","Dim Sum","Chicken Machboos"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Cambodia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Bangladesh","South Korea"],"question":"In which country is the city of Bandung?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Realism","incorrectAnswers":["Italian Renaissance","Cubism","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Sleepers\" by Gustave Courbet is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur C. Clarke","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","C. S. Lewis","H. G. Wells"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Rendezvous with Rama'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Honolulu","incorrectAnswers":["Hilo","Kailua","Maui"],"question":"What is the capital of Hawaii?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","China","The Middle East"],"question":"Where in the world are pumpkins originally from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Haggis ","incorrectAnswers":["Neeps and Tatties","Pizza Crunch","Cullen Skink"],"question":"Which Scottish Dish Is Boiled In The Stomach Lining Of A Sheep?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venice","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Milan","Naples"],"question":"In which city is the Bridge of Sighs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Edmund Hillary","incorrectAnswers":["George Mallory","Nirmal Purja","Denis Urubko"],"question":"Who was the mountaineer who in 1953, together with Sherpa Tenzing Norgay, became the first person to reach the summit of Mount Everest?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tabasco sauce","incorrectAnswers":["Bechemel Sauce","Soy sauce","Jelly sauce"],"question":"Which of these is a type of hot sauce?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Austria ","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Belgium","Switzerland"],"question":"'Sachertorte' is a chocolate cake from which country? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Cinderella story. Outta nowhere. A former greenskeeper, now, about to become the Masters champion. It looks like a mirac...It's in the hole! It's in the hole! It's in the hole!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"As God is my witness, I'll never be hungry again.\"","\"Open the pod bay doors, please, HAL.\"","\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Caddyshack'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The l in 'long'","incorrectAnswers":["The m in 'mother'","The f in 'fish'","The k in 'sock'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of an approximant sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Digestion","incorrectAnswers":["Excretion","Absorption","Respiration"],"question":"What is the technical term for the process of breaking down food?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VIII","incorrectAnswers":["Edward VI","Mary I","Elizabeth I"],"question":"Which king of England, who died in 1547, was survived by his wife Catherine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Barometer ","incorrectAnswers":["A Hydrometer","A Meterometer","An Atmoseter"],"question":"Which Instrument Measures Atmospheric Pressure?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Easter","incorrectAnswers":["Christmas","All Saints' Day","Advent Sunday"],"question":"The date of which Christian festival was fixed in 325AD by the Council of Nicaea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Smiths","incorrectAnswers":["The Cure","Sex Pistols","Nirvana"],"question":"Which band had Morrissey as its frontman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ant-Man","incorrectAnswers":["Spider-Man","Iron Man","Batman"],"question":"In what recent film does Paul Rudd enlist the aid of his insect allies to defeat the villainous Yellow Jacket? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada ","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Australia","Japan"],"question":"Which Country Has The Longest Coastline?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Eye","incorrectAnswers":["Pancreas","Kidney","Testicles"],"question":"In which organ is a clear watery solution known as the 'aqueous humor' found?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["United States","New Zealand","Ireland"],"question":"In which country is the city of Edinburgh?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Emma Thompson","incorrectAnswers":["Kirsten Dunst","Charlize Theron","Sandra Bæ Hovedr"],"question":"Which actress featured in films including Men in Black 3 and Love Actually?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Spain","Australia"],"question":"In which country would you find the Carlsbad Caverns National Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marlon Brando","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Shaw","Glenn Close","Samuel L. Jackson"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Vito Corleone in The Godfather?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Turkish delight","incorrectAnswers":["Baklava","Loukoumades","Halva"],"question":"What type of sweet consists of gelatinous cubes dusted with sugar, with rosewater, bergamot and lemon being common flavors?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kentucky Fried Chicken","incorrectAnswers":["McDonald's","Burger King","Taco Bell"],"question":"Which fast food chain advertises with the slogan\"'It's finger lickin' good!\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Norway","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Sweden","Finland"],"question":"London's Trafalgar Square Christmas tree is traditionally given by which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gregor Mendel","incorrectAnswers":["Francis Galton","Charles Lyell","Sigmund Freud"],"question":"What pioneer of genetics is known for his contemporary work with Darwin in the field of botany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sing with all the voices of the mountain","incorrectAnswers":["Swim with all the water in the river","Speak with all the spirits of the trees","Dance with all the animals in the forest"],"question":"In the Disney movie 'Pocahontas', what does Pocahontas ask if you can do?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Frond","incorrectAnswers":["Raunt","Leaflet","Bough"],"question":"What is the word used for the large, divided leaves of ferns and some palms, which comes from the Latin for \"foliage\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Inquisition","incorrectAnswers":["The Papacy","The Monad","The Cardinality"],"question":"Which Institution Was Founded By The Roman Catholic Church In The 13th Century To Root Out Heresy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Salvador Dalí","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","Cassius Marcellus Coolidge","Vincent van Gogh"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1990","incorrectAnswers":["1983","1971","1999"],"question":"In which year did the Gulf War begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Elephants","incorrectAnswers":["Bald Eagles","Chimpanzees","Earthworms"],"question":"Which animal communicates in sound waves below the frequency that humans can hear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The fetus","incorrectAnswers":["The future","Feet","Fetishes"],"question":"What is Fetology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Paraguay","Chile"],"question":"Montevideo Is The Capital Of Which South American Country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jaguar","incorrectAnswers":["Chevrolet","Aston Martin","Ferrari"],"question":"The XK120 was a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Francisco Pizarro","incorrectAnswers":["Hernando Cortez","Philip Alberto","Manuel Cruz"],"question":"Who was the conquistador who claimed Inca lands for Spain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laura Linney","incorrectAnswers":["Keira Knightley","Frances Fisher","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including The Truman Show and Mystic River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"We'll always have Paris.\"","\"Yo, Adrian!\"","\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Apocalypse Now'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album '...And Justice for All'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln ","incorrectAnswers":["Gerald Ford","Herbert Hoover","Ulysses S. Grant"],"question":"Who was the 16th president of the USA, in term during the period 1861–1865?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Groot","incorrectAnswers":["Clint Barton","Ego","Drax the Destroyer"],"question":"Vin Diesel plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Reykjavik","incorrectAnswers":["Nicosia","Minsk","Palikir"],"question":"What is the capital city of Iceland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Don Quixote","incorrectAnswers":["The Diary of a Chambermaid","The Neverending Story","Orlando Furioso"],"question":"In which book does 'Sancho Panza' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo and Juliet","Macbeth","Othello"],"question":"In which Shakespeare play does the title character say the famous line: \"A man may fish with the worm that hath eat of a king, and eat of the fish that hath fed of that worm\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yangon","incorrectAnswers":["Suwon","Seoul","Hanoi"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Burma?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Albania ","incorrectAnswers":["India","South Africa","Turkey"],"question":"Which country uses a Lek as a unit of currency?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burma","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Laos","Meenmar"],"question":"Myanmar was known as _____________ until 1989.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mathematician and scientist.","incorrectAnswers":["Victorian novelist.","The first sailor to circumnavigate the earth.","Surgeon who pioneered the use of sterilisation and antiseptic."],"question":"Which of the following describes Isaac Newton?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Indiana Jones","incorrectAnswers":["James Bond","Bruce Wayne","Luke Skywalker"],"question":"Which famous character went for a \"Last Crusade\" in a 1989 film?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Tubular pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is ditalini?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dune","incorrectAnswers":["Das Boot","Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","Vertigo"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A noble family becomes embroiled in a war for control over the galaxy's most valuable asset.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Boxing","Tennis","Snooker"],"question":"In which sport does Lee Westwood play?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Justin Timberlake","incorrectAnswers":["Rihanna","Mariah Carey","Usher"],"question":"With whom was Janet Jackson performing a duet, when she 'popped out' at the 2004 Superbowl?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grapes","incorrectAnswers":["Apples","Cherries","Dates"],"question":"Which fruit is typically used to make wine?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Earth","Venus","Jupiter"],"question":"What is the second smallest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sandra Bullock","incorrectAnswers":["Charlize Theron","Emma Thompson","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Crash and Speed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","San Marino","Poland"],"question":"Copenhagen is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"FC Cincinnati","incorrectAnswers":["Cincinnati Orioles","Cincinnati Dolphins","Sporting Cincinnati"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Cincinnati?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Fassbender","incorrectAnswers":["Gerard Butler","Jim Carrey","Robert Redford"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Inglourious Basterds and 12 Years a Slave?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Greece ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Russia","Pakistan"],"question":"In which country would you expect to be served a yoghurt-based starter called 'tzatziki'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I know who I am. I’m the dude playing a dude disguised as another dude!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I live my life a quarter mile at a time.\"","\"Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?\"","\"Not my tempo.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Tropic Thunder'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Glenn Close","incorrectAnswers":["Kristin Scott Thomas","Naomi Watts","Penélope Cruz"],"question":"Which actress has featured in both Warcraft and 101 Dalmatians?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","incorrectAnswers":["Henry VIII","Richard III","Mark Lancaster"],"question":"Who took the title \"Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of England, Scotland, and Ireland\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Barbie","incorrectAnswers":["GI Joe","Stretch Armstrong","Beanie Babies"],"question":"What Toy Still Hugely Popular Today First Went On Sale In 1959 Costing Just $3","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Track and field","Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Chris Evert associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Giovanni Boccaccio","incorrectAnswers":["Dante Alighieri","Agatha Christie","Stephenie Meyer"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Decameron'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist released the album 'Hounds of Love'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada ","incorrectAnswers":["China","Brazil","Russia"],"question":"What is the second largest country in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Overcoat'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Pilgrims","incorrectAnswers":["The Conquistadors","The Vikings","The Kingsmen"],"question":"What group landed in America in 1620?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jean Auguste Dominique Ingres","incorrectAnswers":["Caravaggio","Jackson Pollock","El Greco"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Grand Odalisque\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bark","incorrectAnswers":["Roots","Leaves","Berries"],"question":"From what part of a tree was aspirin originally extracted?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Poppycock","incorrectAnswers":["Dipthong","Ragamuffin","Quomodocunquizing"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'nonsense'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Engineer who helped develop radio transmission.","incorrectAnswers":["Roman ruler who oversaw the demise of the Roman Republic to be replaced with a Roman Emperor.","Poet and playwright.","Renaissance mathematician and astronomer who believed Sun was the centre of the Universe - rather than Earth."],"question":"Which of the following describes Guglielmo Marconi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1948","incorrectAnswers":["1890","1966","2002"],"question":"When did the United States enact the Marshall Plan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Galileo Galilei","incorrectAnswers":["Nicolas Copernicus","Thomas Edison","Alexander Fleming"],"question":"Who invented the telescope?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Quran","incorrectAnswers":["Bible","Torah","Gita"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic holy book?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Nicholas Nickleby'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Long March","incorrectAnswers":["The Trail of Tears","The Mao Manouver","The Maontain Retreat"],"question":"What do historians call the military retreat made by Mao to evade the Kuomintang army?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Serbia","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Ghana","Equador"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink slivovitz?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Hanks","incorrectAnswers":["Ewan McGregor","Will Smith","Tom Cruise"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Forrest Gump and Apollo 13?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Old Man and the Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Remains of the Day","Their Eyes Were Watching God","The Color Purple"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Santiago'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Zaire","incorrectAnswers":["Algeria","Guatemala","Vietnam"],"question":"Muhammad Ali Took On George Foreman In The 'Rumble In The Jungle''. In what Country Did This Take Place?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","Africa","South America"],"question":"Where in the world are apricots originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Leonardo da Vinci","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Sandro Botticelli","Vincent van Gogh"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Last Supper\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Charles","incorrectAnswers":["William","Orson","Jacob"],"question":"What is the first name of the character 'Citizen Kane' in the film of the same name?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the nose and its diseases","incorrectAnswers":["ants","origin of life","the age of trees and the records in their rings"],"question":"What is Rhinology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Not Safe For Life","incorrectAnswers":["New Standard For Living","Nearly Saw First Love","No Sales For Losers"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'NSFL' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ottawa","incorrectAnswers":["Vancouver","Montreal","Quebec City"],"question":"What is the capital city of Canada?","difficulty":"hard"},